A Finding Aid to the Erwin Panofsky Papers, 1904-1990 (bulk dates 1920-1968), in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Erwin Panofsky papers
1904-1990
bulk 1920-1968
Archives of American Art
Panofsky, Erwin, 1892-1968
AAA.panoerwi
Archival Resource Key
19.8 Cubic feet
The papers of Erwin Panofsky measure 19.8 linear feet and are dated 1904-1990 (bulk dates 1920-1968). They consist of correspondence, writings, biographical material, and printed material documenting Panofsky's career as an art historian, teacher, and writer. The Panofsky papers are comprised mainly of correspondence with colleagues, scholars, students, art dealers, galleries and museums, libraries, colleges and universities, organizations, and periodicals.
Biographical Note
Erwin Panofsky (1892-1968), a native of Hannover, Germany, grew up in Berlin where he received a classical education at the Joachimsthalsches Gymnasium. He then studied at the universities of Berlin, Munich and Freiburg/Breslau. After earning a Ph. D. in 1914 from the University of Freiburg, Panofsky spent three years on post-doctoral study in Berlin, and during this period, married fellow student and art historian Dorothea (Dora) Mosse.
Although primarily a scholar of Gothic and Renaissance art, Panofsky had wide interests. Erwin Panofsky was a highly respected and influential scholar who was a much loved, generous, and encouraging teacher of several generations of productive scholars. Many students became his life long friends, and quite a few of them considered Panofsky the greatest teacher they had ever encountered.
He taught at the University of Hamburg from 1920 to1933, and during this period began to develop iconographic approaches to interpreting art through analysis of its subject matter's symbols, themes, and history. His work in this area eventually had international influence in the development of art history as a discipline.
Beginning in 1931, Panofsky taught at New York University, spending alternate semesters at the University of Hamburg until the Nazis dismissed all Jewish officials. He and his family fled Germany and came to the United States in 1933. During the academic year 1934/35, Panofsky held concurrent appointments at both New York University and Princeton University. He joined the faculty of the newly formed Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton, New Jersey, in 1935, where he remained until his retirement in 1962. In addition, he continued to teach graduate seminars at New York University and Princeton Universtiy.
He was a prolific writer, and his many books and articles represent some of the 20th century's most important writings in the field of art history, particularly in the realm of iconography. Among his books are: "Idea": Ein Beitrag zur Begriffsgeschichte der älteren Kunstheorie (1924) [translated later as Idea, The History of a Concept], Studies in Iconology (1939), Codex Huygens and Leonardo da Vinci's Art Theory (1940), The Life and Art of Albrecht Dürer (1943), Abbot Suger on the Abbey Church of St. Denis and Its Art Treasures (1946), Gothic Architecture and Scholasticism (1951), Early Netherlandish Painting: Its Origins and Character (1953), Meaning and the Visual Arts (1950), Renaissance and Renascences in Western Art (1960), The Iconography of Correggio's Camera di San Paolo (1961), and Problems in Titian, Mostly Iconographic (1964).
Panofsky wrote on subjects other than art history. He was an authority on Mozart, and also wrote about the history of cinema. His 1934 article "On Movies" (originally published in Princeton University's Bulletin of the Department of Art and Archaeology), remains a highly regarded work on the subject.
The recipient of numerous honorary degrees, Panofsky most prized the first from the University of Utrecht, 1936, as it brought great satisfaction at a time when he was still coping with the trauma of expatriation. He was a member of the American Philosophical Society, the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, the British Academy, and several other foreign academies. In 1962, Panofsky received the Haskins Medal awarded by The Medieval Academy of America for a distinguished book in medieval history.
His wife Dora Mosse Panofsky died in 1965; in 1966, he married Gerda Soergel, also an art historian. Erwin Panofsky died in Princeton, New Jersey, March 14, 1968.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Erwin Panofsky measure 19.8 linear feet and are dated 1904-1990 (bulk dates 1920-1968). They consist of correspondence, writings, biographical material, and printed material documenting Panofsky's career as an art historian, teacher, and writer.
The Panofsky papers are comprised mainly of correspondence with colleagues, scholars, students, art dealers, galleries and museums, libraries, colleges and universities, organizations, and periodicals. Among the correspondents are colleagues, scholars, students, art dealers, galleries and museums, libraries, colleges and universities, organizations, and periodicals. Correspondents include: Udo von Alvensleben, Walter William Spencer Cook, Paul Coremans, Walter Friedländer, William S. Heckscher, Ludwig H. Heydenreich, Horst Janson, Adolf Katzenellenbogen, Richard Krauatheimer, Edward E. Lowinsky, Millard Meiss, Gert van Osten, Richard Salomon, Craig Smyth, Wolfgang Stechow, Booth and Betty Tarkington, Egon Verheyen, and Wilhelm Vöge.
Writings by Panofsky include drafts, notes, and manuscripts of articles, book reviews, books, and lectures. Biographical material consists of awards and certificates, diplomas (including many honorary degrees), and membership certificates. Among the printed material are articles and clippings about or mentioning Panofsky, programs for graduation ceremonies at which Panofsky was awarded honorary degrees, reviews of Panofsky's books, obituaries, and memorial programs and tributes.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 4 series:
Missing Title
Series 1: Correspondence, 1921-1978, undated (Boxes 1-16; 16 linear ft.; Reels 2108- 2128)
Series 2: Writings, 1915-1968, undated (Boxes 17-19; 2.3 linear ft.)
Series 3: Biographical Information, 1905-1967 (Boxes 19-21; 0.5 linear ft.)
Series 4: Printed Material, 1904-1990, undated (Box 19; 0.5 linear ft.)
Related Material
Among the Archives' holdings is a collection of letters from Erwin Panofsky to art historians Wolfgang Stechow (1930-1931) and Lili Fröhlich-Bum (1931), and to Brooklyn Museum art librarian William B. Walker (1960) which is available on 35-mm microfilm reel 5136, frames 812-824. The letters to Stechow were written as he was preparing a review of Panofsky's book, Hercules am Scheidewege und andere antike Bildstoffe inder neueren Kunst, and provide additional information not found in the book itself. The letter to Mr. Walke is in Englishe, and the remainder are in German. The originals are still in the possession of Irving Lavin, who found them in Stechow's copy of Hercules am Scsheidewege given him by Mrs. Stechow.
Provenance
The Erwin Panofsky papers were donated by his widow, Dr. Gerda Soergel Panofsky, in 1979 and 1990.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Patrons must use microfilm copy. Use of the unmicrofilmed portion requires an appointment and is limited to the Washington, D.C. research facility.
Alternative Forms Available
Portions of the collection are available on 35 mm microfilm reels 2108-2128 at the Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan.
Art historians -- New Jersey -- Princeton; Art -- Study and teaching
- Correspondence, 1921-1978, undated; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 1-16; 16 linear ft. Reels 2108-2128)
  Scope and Contents note
  Erwin Panofsky's correspondence documents his research, writing, teaching, lecturing, and participation in professional organizations. It reflects his own academic interests and expertise - Medieval, Gothic, and Renaissance art, history, and iconography, and those of his many correspondents.
  His most prolific correspondents include: Udo von Alvensleben, Walter William Spencer Cook, Paul Coremans, Walter Friedländer, William S. Heckscher, Ludwig H. Heydenreich, Horst W. Janson, Adolf Katzenellenbogen, Richard Krautheimer, Edward E. Lowinsky, Millard Meiss, Gert von der Osten, Richard Salomon, Craig Smyth, Wolfgang Stechow, Booth and Betty Tarkington, Egon Verheyen, and Wilhelm Vöge.
  1.8: Miscellaneous, arranged by subject, includes: requests for reviews, contributions to encyclopedias and dictionaries, and requests to write books; acknowledgements and thank you letters, 70th birthday congratulations; U.S. government, embassies and consulates. 1.9: Unfilmed Correspondence, received many years after microfilming was completed, is arranged chronologically and overlaps the dates and categories of correspondents represented in the preceding subseries.
  Arrangement note
  This series is arranged into 9 subseries. Subseries 1.2, 1.3 and 1.4 are arranged alphabetically by geographical location. Subseries 1.9 is in chronological order. All remaining subseries are arranged alphabetically.
  1.1: Colleagues, Scholars, Students and Other Individuals, 1921-1978, undated (Reels 2108-2124)
  1.2: Art Dealers, 1932-1967 (Reels 2124-2125)
  1.3: Galleries and Museums, 1925-1968 (Reel 2125)
  1.4: Libraries, 1941-1967 (Reels 2125-2126)
  1.5: Colleges, Universities, and Institutes, 1936-1968, undated (Reels 2126-2127)
  1.6: Organizations, Societies, and Congresses, 1937-1967 (Reel 2127)
  1.7: Periodicals, 1937-1967 (Reel 2127)
  1.8: Miscellaneous, 1940-1969 (Reels 2127-2128)
  1.9: Unfilmed Correspondence, 1925-1967, undated (unfilmed)
  Existence and Location of Copies
  Correspondence is on reels 2108-2128.Correspondence is on reels 2108-2128.
  - Colleagues, Scholars, Students and Other Individuals, 1921-1978, undated; 1.1; Archival Resource Key
    Correspondence is available on reels 2108-2124. Reel 2108: A-Bin; Reel 2109: Bis-Brin; Reel 2110: Brin-Cool; Reel 2111: Cool-Dow; Reel 2112: Dow-Fren; Reel 2113: Freu-Grin; Reel 2114: Grip-Hey; Reel 2115: Hey-Kal; Reel 2116: Kal-Lavin; Reel 2117: Lavin-Mar; Reel 2118: Mar-No; Reel 2119: No-Po; Reel 2120: Po-Sa; Reel 2121: Sa-Sn; Reel 2122: Sn-Ta; Reel 2123: Ta-Wac; Reel 2124: Wa-Zu.
    - A, General (single letters, Aaron - Axinn), 1936-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Aaron, Maxine G.
      Abbott, John E.
      Harry N. Abrams, Inc.
      Adams, Gillian
      Adler, Alfred
      Ahlborn, Richard E.
      Albers, Josef
      Albers-Schoenberg, E.
      Alef, Gustave
      Alexandr, Robert C.
      Allan, Donald J.
      Allen, D. C.
      Allen, David,
      Allenby, Amy Ingeborg
      Allers, Rudolf
      Alley, Elizabeth D.
      Altman, Julius
      Amberg, George
      Ames, Winslow
      D'Ancora
      Anderson, Edgar
      Anderson, Lawrence B.
      Anderson, Martha
      Anderson, Robert R.
      Anderson, Zane
      Andrade, D. José Pita
      Andreisse, A.
      Antal, Friedrich
      Anthony, Robert W.
      Anzelewski, Fedja
      Apel, Willi
      Aprá, Adriano
      Armstrong, Amy
      Arnold, Frederick L.
      Aronsohn, Harold N.
      Ash, Graham Baron
      Ashron, Dore
      Askew, Kirk, Jr.
      Atwood, Earle R.
      Auzas, P. M.
      Axinn, Sidney
    - Ackerman, 1947-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Ackerman, Gerald
      Ackerman, James
    - Adams, Frederick B., Jr., 1951-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Adhémar, 1946-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Adhémar, Hélène
      Adhémar, Jean
    - Alexander - Alpatov, Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 5)
      Alexander, Paul J.
      Alföldi, Andrew
      Alker, Hermann
      Alpatov, Michael
    - Alvensleben, Udo von, 1928-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6-7)
    - d'Alverny - Ameisenowa, Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 8)
      d'Alverny, Marie-Thérèse
      Alyea, Herbert N.
      Ameisenowa, Zofia
    - Argan, Giulio Carlo, 1956-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Aries - Arnolds, 1940-1968, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Aries, Robert S.
      Arnheim, Rudolf
      Arnason, H. Harvard
      Arnolds, Günter
    - Askew - Aubert, 1952-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Askew, Pamela
      Aubert, Marcel
    - Auerbach, Erich, 1949-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Aurenhammer, Hans, 1956-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Aydelotte, 1944-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Aydelotte, Frank
      Aydelotte, William O.
    - B, General (single letters, Bailey - Blair), 1937-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Bailey, Stephen K.
      Bainton, Roland H.
      Baker, Carlos
      Bannister, Turpin
      Barbour, J. Murray
      Barker, John W.
      Barnhart, Clarence L.
      Barnouw, A. J.
      Baron, H.
      Barton, Jess
      Bassi, Stelio
      Bates, Donald G.
      Baudry, J.
      Bayón, Damián Carlos
      Beaujouan, Guy
      Becker, Marion R.
      Beckley, Quitman
      Behling, Lottlisa
      Belangie, W. M.
      Belen, Van der, Jack and Herman Liebaers
      Beller, Elmer
      Bellinger, Alfred R.
      Belluschi, Pietro
      Belt, Elmer
      Berenson, Bernard [copy from S. J. Camp]
      Berg, Gösta
      Van der Berg-Noë
      Berger, Pamela
      Bergamnn, Rosemarie
      Berry, Francis
      Bertelli, Dr. and Mrs. Carlo
      Biberman, Herbert
      Bielefeld, Erwin
      Bishop, Katherine
      Blair, David
      Blair, Madeline S.
    - B, General (single letters, de Blanc - Brown), 1946-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 16)
      de Blanc, George G.
      Blanco-Gguinaga, Carlos
      Bloch, Robert
      Blom, Frans
      Blue Card, Inc.
      Bock von Wülfingen, Ordenberg
      Boehringer, Erioco
      Boggs, Jean S.
      Bonow, Eunice R.
      Bony, Mary
      Borgerhoff, E.
      Borromeo d'Adda, Contessa Orietta
      Bosi, Maria
      Böttcher, Otto
      Botte, Paul
      Bouscaren, Louis H. G.
      Bowie, Theodore
      Boyle, Kay
      Brandt, Joseph A.
      Breasted, James H., Jr.
      Breithaumpt, Erwin W.
      Brody, Jules
      Brommer, Frank
      Brooks, H. Allen, Jr.
      Brosemann, Marianne
      Brossman, Martin
      Brown, Estelle
      Brown, Harcourt
      Brown, J. Douglas
      Brown, Louise Fargo
    - B, General (single letters, Brubaker - Buxbaum), 1948-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Brubaker, Elisabeth Ann
      Bruckmann, Verlag F.
      Bruner, Louise
      Brusselle, M. A. Fr.
      Buchholz, Sister Regina
      Buchoff, Barry
      Buchdruck, Buehler
      Buerger, Janet
      Bukofzer, Manfred F.
      Bulatkin, Eleanor W.
      Bundy, McGeorge
      Burkhardt, Frederick
      Burman, Shibdlas
      Burroughs, Alan
      Buuren, D. M. van
      Buxbaum, Rhoda
    - Bacgihofer - Badt, 1938-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Bacgihofer, Ludwig
      Badt, Kurt
    - Baer, Kathi Meyer-Baer, 1954-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Baets - Bailly, 1952-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Baets, Rev. P.M.J. de
      Baeyns, Herman
      Bailly, Ellen H.
    - Bak, Robert C., 1963-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Baldass - Baránszy-Jób, Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Baldass, Ludwig
      Bandmann, Günter
      Baránszy-Jób, László
    - Barasch, Moses, 1957-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Bardon - Barton, 1945-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Bardon, Françoiose
      Bargebuhr, Frederick P.
      Baron, Hans
      Barton, Samuel G.
    - Barr, Alfred H., Jr. and Margaret ("Daisy"), 1945-1965, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Barzun - Battisti, 1955-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 26)
      Barzun, Jacques
      Baticle, Jeannine
      Battisti, Eugenio
    - Bauch, Kurt, 1956-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Bauer - Bergemann, 1951-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Bauer, Lucie
      Beck, James N
      Beckley, Rev. Quitman F.
      Begemann, Egbert Heverkamp
    - Benesch - Bergerhoff, 1945-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Scope and Contents
      Benesch, Otto
      Berger, Klaus
      Bergerhoff, Renate
    - Bergström - Berliner, 1936-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 30)
      Bergström, Ingvar
      Berliner, R. R.
    - Bernheimer, Richard, 1944-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Bertin-Mourot, Thérèse, 1946-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Bettagno - Beutler, 1961-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Bettagno, Alessandro
      Beutler, Christian
    - Bialostocki, Jan, 1953-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Bieber, Margarete, 1941-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Bier, Justus, 1949-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Billikopf, Jacob, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Bing, Gertrude, 1925-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Bischoff, Bernhard, 1956-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Birkmeyer, Karl M., 1958-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Björck, Gudmund, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - von Blanckenhagen, P. H., 1933-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bloch, Peter, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Bloch, Vitale, 1937-1957, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Blunt, Anthony, 1957-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Boas, George, 1936-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Bober, Harry, 1941-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Bober, Phyllis Pray (Mrs. Harry Bober), 1955-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Bodnar, Rev. Edward, 1959-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Bonicatti, Maurizio, 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Bony, Jean, 1954-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Borsook, Eve, 1962-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Boskovits, Miklós, 1962-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Boström, Kjell, 1946-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Bowles, Edmund A., 1951-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Boyd, Juilian P., 1945-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Branca, Vittore, 1960-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Brand-Philip, Lotte (Foerster), 1949-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Branner, Robert, 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Brauen, Fred, 1962-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Braunfels, Wolfgang, 1954-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Breckenridge, James, 1949-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Breitenbach, Edgar, 1927-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Brendel, Otto, 1958-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Briegler, Peter H., 1949-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Brincard, Louis, 1949-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Brinkerhoff, Dericksen M., 1948-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Brion-Guérry, Liliane, 1951-1967, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Brizio, Anna Maria, circa 1950-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Broadly, Hugh, 1950-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Brown, Milton, 1937-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Brummer, H. H., 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Bruyn, Josua, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Bucher, François, 1961-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Buchthal, Hugo H., 1933-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Buddensieg, Tilmann, 1958-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Bueckenhoudt, M. Walter, 1960-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Burden-Moller, Roland, 1953-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Burke, William L., 1950-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Burkhard, Arthur, 1953-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Burrage, Bob and Mildred G., 1943-1971, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Buschbeck, Ernest, 1950-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Bush-Brown, Albert, 1949-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Byvanck, A. W., 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - C, General (single leltters, Cabaniss - Cutler), 1937-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 47)
      Cabaniss, Allen
      Calhoun, Robert L.
      Calvesi, Maurizio
      Cambrari, Archeveche de
      Caplan, Judith
      Caponigri, A. Robert
      Carey, Graham
      Carmichael, Peter A.
      Carrière, R.
      Carrith, David
      Carroll, Eugene A.
      Cassirer, Kurt
      Cassirer, Tom
      Caterini, Styde
      Cederlöf, Olle
      Cervene, Richard
      Chadraba, Rudolf
      Chadwick-Collins, Mrs. James
      Chaikin, Nathan
      Chakravarty, Amiya
      Chambers, F. P.
      Chartier, chanoine Maurice
      Cheadle, Helen
      Cirker, Hayward
      Claflin, Agnes
      Clark, John S.
      Claybrook, Priscilla Leigh
      Clements, Robert J.
      Cliver, E. Blaine
      Clogan, Paul M.
      Cloulas-Brousseau, Annie
      Coburn, Kathleen
      Coe, William J.
      Cohn, Alfred E.
      Cohn, Werner [from Millard Meiss]
      Coles, Margot J.
      Colie, Rosalie L.
      Commanger, Henry Steele
      Comstock, Francis A.
      Conan, A.
      Cooke, H. Lester
      Corbett, Dorothy
      Cornelius, Du Pont
      Cornell, Henrik
      Couprie, L. D.
      Courant, R.
      Cox, Trenchard
      Coyle, Dan
      Craig, Gordon
      Crane, Mrs. W. Murray
      Crocker, Lester G.
      Crowlie, A. C.
      Curl, Huldah
      Curran, Thomas
      Cutler, Anthony
    - Callisen - Campbell, 1951-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48)
      Callisen, Sterling A.
      Campbell, Malcolm
    - Canaday, John, 1943-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Carandente - Cartier, 1950-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 50)
      Carandente, Giobanni
      Carey, Peter, 1954-1965
      Cartier, David Giles, 1950-1962
    - Castelli - Cetto, 1951-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 51)
      Castelli, Enrico
      Catlin, Stanton L.
      Cetto, Anna Maria
    - Chastel, André, 1949-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Châtelet, Albert, 1954-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Cherniss, Harold F., 1946-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Chew, Samuel C. and Lucy E., 1944-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Christie, Ives, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Citroen - Clemens, 1951-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 57)
      Citroen, K. A.
      Clagett, Marshall
      Clemens, Walter
    - Clement - Clowes, 1942-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 58)
      Clement, Paul A.
      Clowes, Edith W. and Clowes, G.H.A. (The Clowes Fund)
    - Coffin, David Robbins, 1950-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Cohen - Cohn, 1962-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Cohen, Bernard I.
      Cohn, Marjorie
    - Conant, Judith W., 1964-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Conant - Conkwright, 1951-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Conant, Kenneth John
      Conkwright, P. J.
    - Cook, Walter William Spencer, 1937-1961, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    - Cooledge, Harold N., 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 7)